Most bugs reported in bug bounty are
mediums or highs where yes, you can leak
some data, but also the attack has some
prerequisite. Critical is a rare thing,
but not for my today's guest. Not for
Alex Chapman, who seems to have cracked
the code and most of the bugs he finds
are critical. Enjoy the interview.
Hello Alex, thank you so much for
joining me for this interview.
For those of you who don't know you yet,
can you please introduce yourself and
tell us how did you get to to the point
you're currently at?
Great. Hey. So, my name's Alex Chapman,
AJX Chapman on pretty much all program
platforms and social media.
Um, I've been doing security
well, professionally since 2007. So,
that's What is that?
15, 16 years. That's a lot.
Um,
but then been been interested since I
could kind of type on a computer really.
Um, kind of one of those typical
misspent youths of spending all of the
all of my time in in front of the
computer and then eventually were like
thinking, oh, how does this work? And
and what do I do with this?
Um, so yeah, I've
just been been interested in security
for
well,
over three decades now.
Um, and
managed to to turn it into a career.
Yeah.
What was your first professional job in
in the area of cybersecurity?
Uh, so I was a pen tester
straight out of university for about
10 years. I was in the kind of
consulting realm. Uh, doing pen testing,
moving on to red teaming and then
security research.
Um, so kind of
all the sides of of the technical
consulting.
Was it mainly web-based hacking that you
did or was it more binary exploitation
or a mix of everything?
So,
started off primarily web-based. I I
like to describe myself as the worst web
app tester.
Um, it's not something I'm interested
in, but it's something that we have to
do a lot of. Um, so I was always
interested in binary exploitation if I
could ever get
get those jobs. Um, and then moving into
kind of red teaming, that's where I got
a lot more
interested and involved with actual
exploitation. So, I was writing
browser browser plugin exploits for a
couple of years to kind of break into
user systems and kind of pivot from
there into to attack corporate systems.
And now you're a full-time bug bounty
hunter. How long have you been a
full-time bug bounty hunter for?
Uh, so started full-time bug bounty in
2019. So, again,
my math is pretty bad, but I think
that's getting on about five years. Um,
Yeah, that's five years. Um, yeah, it's
it is one of the best jobs I've I've
had, so.
Yeah, it is, although I don't know many
people that have been doing it full-time
for for five years. That's also why I
wanted to a lot to to interview, but
let's get to to this full-time bug
bounty hunting aspects a bit later. So,
let's start with your hacking style. You
just told us you're a
the worst web hacker out there, yet you
find incredible incredibly critical and
and high-risk vulnerabilities
everywhere. So, if you're a bad web
hacker, what are your good sides then?
So, I
I I'd like to look at a lot of uh
the interactions between complex systems
is is how I like to describe it. So,
where web app meets some other system,
whether that's kind of the uh, interface
into a CI/CD pipeline or a web app that
runs um,
offering system commands and and and
other things. If I can find out that's
what's going on, I then much rather jump
in to work out what that command is
doing or or what the program it's
running in the back end is doing and
kind of take that apart.
So, do you specifically when when
hacking you sort of
kind of ignore all the functionalities
that a lot of us look for like XSS, like
IDORs, like authentication? You strictly
look for these functionalities that that
you think may run commands under the
hood or something like this?
Um,
pretty much. I mean, ignore is is going
a bit far, but I think I've
if I look back in my
HackerOne stats, I think I've probably
only reported like one IDOR ever.
Um, and that's going back seven years on
the platform. Um, yeah.
XSS I I reluctantly search for if I need
it for another bug or part of a bug
chain. Uh, and that's something I've
been doing a lot recently with browser
exploitation
and exploiting server-side browsers.
Um, where the XSS is required to run
your own code in a server-side browser
in order to exploit that.
Um, and that's kind of been a been a
heavy focus of mine for about two years
now.
Yeah, so so
what what exactly functionalities you
think are often what you find auditing?
Because from from what you said, like
the the functionality of running a
headless browser or running system level
commands in many simple web apps that
that I see in in a lot of bug bounty
programs as well, I don't see
functionalities that would that would do
it. What what functionalities do you
usually like look for specifically?
Yeah, that's really good question. So,
for certainly for server-side browsers,
it's more often than not it's kind of
PDF rendering. Um, so anywhere a
a web application gives back a PDF with
data that you control, it's often going
to go through either a server-side
browser Chrome
um,
or something slightly older PhantomJS or
XML to PDF
XHTML to PDF.
Or there are some dedicated PDF
libraries that don't use browsers, but
they're
not used quite so much in my experience.
So, when you find a functionality that
let's say you renders a PDF with a
report or something, what is the next
step? Do you try to identify which
library is used to render this PDF or
the the browser? What's the next one?
Yeah, so
if I can
do that without a cross-site scripting,
that's that's obviously my
um, my preferred way of doing it. So,
I'll I'll try and work out what browser
it is. If I can get it to call out to a
to a server that I control, you can
normally fingerprint it or or check out
the user agent.
Um, and get a get a good idea from that
point.
If you don't have that level of control,
I do need to start looking and and going
after the kind of the cross-site
scripting bugs to try and
try and get your own get my own payloads
in there to to get out of that step.
And
also we have a
a question from Johan Carlson about the
browser exploitation.
Has the browser stuff become a grind or
is it still interesting? Is there a fear
of changing paths now that lots seem to
it? Yeah, I mean, that's the question
from Johan. Really interesting question
when I saw that one pop up on Twitter.
So, I've been doing browser exploitation
bug bounty for I checked out like nearly
two years to the month. I think it was
actually July 2022 was the first bug I
submitted. Um, and that was for a live
hacking event in Vegas.
Um, I I knew nothing about browser ex
very little about browser exploitation
at this point. Um, and I just saw they
were using an old version of Chrome to
um,
to render user provided HTML. I thought,
okay, that's obviously an issue. Um, it
was getting towards the end of the or
when I was just about to stop traveling,
so I was like, okay, just submit the
issue and
I'll focus on it a
bit later.
And they came back and they said, yeah,
we're aware of that,
but if you can actually exploit this
browser for remote code execution, we
will we will pay the issue.
Uh, and I was just I think I was about
an hour away from getting onto a 14-hour
flight. So, I thought, all right, okay.
See what I can do. Download as much
information as I could onto my laptop
about kind of browser exploitation and
um, Chrome issues and all the rest of
it. Had really good read through on the
flight. It's kind of really good primer.
And then I just started going through
the um,
uh,
Chrome's
um, issue um,
reporting
application is is actually open to the
public certainly with um, security
issues. They tend to open them up after
about 14 weeks of the issue being fixed.
So, I was going through all these old
um,
bug reports on the on the Chrome issue
reporter and found one or two with proof
of concepts.
And kind of
managed to stay up very late on several
nights and actually got a working
um, browser exploit, which was a big
rush for me and actually was one of my
biggest ever bounties uh, from that
event.
And that was two years ago, so I kind of
kept up that interest for for two years
and it was it's been pretty much all
I've been looking for
um, for about two years.
But it's got to the point where I know
where a lot of these server-side
browsers are in programs.
I exploit it, they fix it,
I kind of wait
two or three months,
a new bug comes out, they don't patch
it, I exploit it, they fix it. I wait a
couple of months,
a new bug comes out, and it it's just
this cycle of now I feel like I'm
chasing patches
and not
a few programs have really kind of
implemented a much more robust patch
policy off my
off my reports and others just haven't.
Um, whilst it's great it's great money
and it's it's good to keep doing it,
it's it has become a bit of a grind now.
So, I think I put out on Twitter the
other week that it's I'm probably going
to start moving away from from those
issues to something that that kind of
captivates that interest for me again.
Yeah, is it still time-consuming at this
point when you already have quite a good
like skill set about after developing
those previous browser exploits, is it
still a lot of time to develop a new
one? Um
it's much less time. Uh
as long as I've got all the building
blocks in place. If there's a if I can
find it or or get a reliable um
set of primitives going, which
can take a while or again, a lot of uh
other people in the kind of Chrome
exploitation space
um do also publish their their kind of
proof of concepts.
Working off those, it can be relatively
quick.
But um it can also I think the last
end-to-end one I did probably took 2
days.
Um Okay.
But that was using some public
knowledge. If a zero knowledge is taken,
couple of weeks, maybe.
Um Okay, couple of weeks is a lot of
Yeah, so it it can be quite
quite labor intensive. And certainly the
um Chrome and V8 team
have implemented quite a few things
recently that don't make it a lot
harder, which um
is frustrating for me, but in general,
it's a obviously a very good thing. Um
Yeah. What exactly sort of let's say me
as a as a web hacker, I've never
exploited in real life any memory
related bug. What would I have to learn
like before even getting to to browser
specific things, what would I have to
learn before to even start thinking
about developing a browser exploit?
Sure. Um
I mean a a general understanding of
program memory layout is is pretty key.
So understanding kind of heap memory, um
stack memory, program memory.
And and I think once you understand kind
of how a program works, it things fall
into place a little bit more.
And understanding that the the kind of
end goal
when you're when you're doing these
things and and kind of the basic steps
to get there. So if you're looking to
run your own code, you need to somehow
get that code into memory
into a a memory page that's
executable.
Um cuz
modern systems mark memory as either
kind of read-write, read-only, or
read-write
or executable. And if you're trying to
execute
a non-executable memory region, it will
just crash out and and won't let you do
it.
Um
And so you need to get your own code
into memory into
an executable page and somehow get the
program to to jump to that.
And once you've got kind of those three
goals in mind,
things do become a little bit more
easier to partition up into those into
those sections.
Um and I I find it very
much easier to uh focus on this kind of
small tasks that
build up the whole, if that makes sense.
Yeah, yeah, definitely that. So always
when learning a new new thing, you just
the first days is just being overwhelmed
because you don't even know when to
start. And when once you see a
particular problem that you need to
solve, let's say how to get my code into
an executable memory, then it's sort of
easier because I know what I want to
achieve.
Yeah, I mean it's it's really
interesting. I I've looked at a lot of
other people's um Chrome exploits and
just been so daunted by them. Like
they're these
kind of 400-line
JavaScript just messes, what
look like messes when you first start
getting into them.
But then if I kind of take it down to
first principles and build it back up
myself,
um by the time I've finished writing it,
it's kind of 600 lines of JavaScript and
I understand it all. Um and then if
somebody else was come along and look at
it, they'd be like, "What is this?"
Um but I I find that really useful. And
I always
write these things myself
um when I'm doing these sorts of ex-
exploits, even if the
an exploit publicly exists.
One for learning
um
from the learning aspect because I
you learn so much in in doing these
things yourself that will then help you
the next time you try and do it.
Um and secondly, I
I don't like the idea of just using
other people's code on
um
third-party systems that I don't if I
don't fully understand it.
Yeah, yeah, I see. Makes sense.
Okay, let's Well, you just told me that
last past 2 years have been mostly doing
uh exploiting the the headless browsers.
But apart from this, what are other
functionalities are are common to have
RCEs in them or at least common to to
execute system-level commands under the
hood?
Um so I used to a lot of kind of CI/CD
pipeline stuff because that's a a big
area where if anything, it's kind of
remote code execution as a service.
Um so
it's allowing you to to run code and
you're you're looking for kind of
uh system interaction bugs at that
point.
Um
And you can often find or at least used
to be able to often find um
areas where they would be running
commands outside of containerized
environments with your input.
Um
it's pretty much very well locked down
now
um over the past kind of 3 4 years
in that area.
Um trying to think Yeah, do do you mean
now when you say CI/CD, do you mean
let's say finding a vulnerability in
GitLab, which like clearly is is in
scope of bug bounty program, or do you
find the a pipeline of a just a normal
program, normal website running around
somewhere?
Uh so yeah, I would have been focusing
on the kind of GitLab, GitHub, side of
it rather than the individual um
repository pipelines.
So more more on the the core of how
things work.
Um just trying to look through some of
the other bugs that I've um exploited
recently.
Um JDBC drivers, so Java database
connectors.
Where you can control
the parameters to a JDBC driver, you can
often find either file read-writes or
code execution from those.
And you see that a lot in things like um
local code environments and and other
things like that.
Um I'm not sure if I've seen it
anywhere. What what exactly
functionality would would this be? Is it
a website allowing you to connect to
your database, your own database?
precisely. So
um a good example would be MySQL.
Um if a website allows you to connect to
your own
MySQL
um or MariaDB
um database instance, you if you can
pass in the JDBC connection parameters,
there's all sorts of things you can do.
So you can enable local file read from
that.
Which then your database server can read
files from the connecting system.
Um you used to be able to I think it's
been removed now, but you used to be
able to enable
uh JavaScript object deserialization.
Um which would well, certainly could
lead to remote code execution. I've I've
exploited that a few times in the past.
Yeah, these are these are super specific
vulnerability class. Yeah, I mean I can
try to think think about programs that
that I used to hack on and
I I've never hacked something that had a
a CI/CD pipeline
or stuff like this. So I guess you just
you have a few websites that you just
come back over and over and over again.
I mean that that's a good point. I tend
to hack on kind of very high-paying
programs. Um if a program doesn't pay
I don't maybe $10,000 for a critical, I
probably won't look at it.
Um and there are not that many of these
programs around.
So
it helps me to kind of know which ones I
want and
kind of which fit my criteria of
high-paying with interesting technical
assets that let you do these sorts of
things.
And then if I find
one type of bug, so for example, these
JDBC drivers, I'll learn as much as I
can about that type of bug.
And then see where else that bug can be
applied within the programs that I hack
on.
Yeah.
Do you do you happen sometimes to find a
vulnerability that
uh is a zero day where you work with
somebody that does a lot of automation
to maybe find instances of of these in
other websites?
That's not something I've I've
personally done um today. I've I've
certainly advised uh a couple of
friends who've uh come across that that
way to uh
to work like that. But uh
a lot of the bugs that I'm looking for
don't necessarily lend themselves to
that sort of um automation.
Yeah, yeah, very much sounds like what
you do is very much deep into the
authentication part of the app.
Yeah, I mean if I could work out a way
of automating it, I'd love it. But um my
my experience with personal
automation has never gone well. So uh
I
I kind of avoid that these days.
Do you automate any part of of process
of hunting for these bugs? No.
No, I'm not
At the moment, I'm a 100% manual hacker.
I'm just getting back around to thinking
about
trying automation again in in some
areas.
Um but
with most of the hacking I'm doing, it
is
kind of code review or
uh reverse engineering and that sort of
thing, which which doesn't do so well
with with automation. When reviewing the
source code, do you
help your manual hacking with I don't
know, Semgrep, CodeQL, or something like
this? Yep, certainly Semgrep, CodeQL.
There was another one for Java that I
can't remember that worked really well
on
um compiled Java files.
I might need to look that one up.
But yeah, all kind of SST
SAST and DAST
tools that I can use in in source code
review, I will.
Yeah, and also about getting the source
code down, do you do you do it when you
just test something that's open source
or do you also sometimes
find a a piece of the closed source
application that you can download
locally and audit locally? How does this
work?
Yeah, if it's if it's closed source, um
but the binary is available, I'll always
kind of pull that down and and see what
I can do with that. So do
um set that up on my local system and do
kind of both active and
so active analysis, so looking at how
it's interacting with the file system
and everything, uh and if it's shelling
out to other commands.
And also do reverse engineering where
where required on that side of things.
Um open source, yeah, 100% I'll
pull the repositories, pull the um
the history, kind of go through and try
and get as as good an understanding of
the of the application as I can.
Um there've been one or two times where
I've come across bugs that can expose
server-side source code.
Um and I've always gone to the program
and said, "Hey, I've got this bug. Do
you mind if I have a look at your source
code?" Uh more often than not they say
no. Like
don't touch it at all. But I've had once
or twice where they said, "Yeah, why
not?"
Really?
Give it a go.
Oh, that's cool.
Yeah, and that's
I Did this result in in other bugs on
the same website?
100%. And that's
that's to me that's always a
a really good sign of a good program.
Um and I will Oh, yeah.
I know that I'll be able to find some
good bugs for them.
Which which is what everyone wants. So
Yeah, and especially you know you you
have access to the source code which you
know what the else has. So
it would definitely motivate me to stay
on this program way way longer than I
usually maybe would just decide to move
on. 100%. I'll stay way longer on this.
Okay, so we have browser exploits, we
have CICD hacking.
Um
what what about like back classes that
that let's say are typical web
vulnerabilities like SQL injection,
XXEs, template injections, nothing like
this?
if I remember correctly, I think I've
submitted one SQL injection
ever.
And again, that was part of a bug chain
to exploit
um something else. So
uh
it's
I just don't really look for them.
And that's
Are you tempted to to like look for
these bugs or
That's
something I've been thinking about a lot
recently. So if I'm getting out of kind
of server-side browser exploitation, I'm
getting out of it so much, so not doing
it 100%. Um
then what am I going to do next? And I
do want to get better at web hacking.
I I will try and look for those sorts of
bugs in future, but uh
just I get bored.
I I don't like just kind of manually
fuzzing
web applications. So
I've got a few ideas on automation and
and how I could try and implement
things, but I know what I'm going to do
is
kind of get
bogged down with the development of a of
a tool or of a Chrome extension or
something and then kind of put it to one
side and go do something else.
Yeah, are you thinking about automation
like big big scale to scan many programs
or more like you log in into the web
application and you try to there
automatically find some bugs?
Yeah, so
on a large scale, I I just don't have
the interest or the dedication to do it.
I've tried to do it a few times in the
past.
Um and I I enjoy the development side of
it too much. So I'll keep adding
features, keep adding features without
ever finding a bug with it.
So I think I I've probably put in
eight months plus of development on
automation like in my oh well five year
uh bug bounty career
and have found zero bugs through
automation. So um
I kind of gave that up in the first few
years.
Yeah, yeah, I see.
Do you keep like because you you hack on
very specific functionalities, do you
keep somewhere the list of which
interesting functionality is in which
program?
Yeah. And then once let's say new new
Chrome Chromium exploit is out, you you
just go to them.
100%. So I've I've just got a
spreadsheet of um
any
whenever I see any third-party tool or
or
um
or command being used, I'll write it
down, write down the version, the
program I found it on, the um kind of
URL I found it. And if I can find the
version, I'll
uh I'll record the version
um as well. But so for example, I've got
uh
70 plus
instances of server-side Chrome
um Oh, wow. that I know about. Not all
of them are exploitable. Um like some of
them will require will require
cross-site scripting or something like
that.
Um Yeah, but I thought it's more like uh
I don't know. I I thought about a way
smaller number. No, no, quite a few. Um
where programs are using LibreOffice in
the background.
Um if I find that, I'll record it.
Uh and just anything like that, I'll
just put in a spreadsheet and if I come
across a vulnerability, uh sorry, an
exploit that works against these things,
um I'll go back to that and reference
the spreadsheet and be like, "Okay,
yeah, I know where that's been used now,
so I can go and
try and exploit that."
Yeah, do you do you have some tricks to
identify what tool is used on the back
end? For example, there's an image
resizing library being used.
Can I is is there a way to somehow
uh check which which exactly library is
being used there?
Yeah, there's uh
the image one's a really good good
example. There are definitely some
uh differences in how image libraries
work on malformed input and
kind of unusual
um
say PNGs or things like that. So you can
always
if you can build up a a big enough
library of these. And this isn't
something I I have actively done. It's
something I really want to do.
Um
and kind of just run it against all
versions of say um
ImageMagick or something and then see
how that process it.
And then run it against the kind of Ruby
image libraries and see how that
processes them.
That's and kind of correlate the two.
That's something I I would be really
interested in
um
looking into more and it's actually on
my on my list of uh of things to
investigate.
Yeah, I I I had a case recently and I
just thought it makes sense, but I
thought how much time would I have to
invest in it and I ended up Oh, huge
amount. But it's but it'd be really
interesting as well. So uh
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It it it it would surely pay off in the
in the long run.
Uh maybe I will ask you about this
specific case. Let's say you have a a
functionality and you upload an
it wasn't actually my bug, but but I was
sort of next next to it. Um uploading an
almost empty BMP file and you see it
being filled with like
either some random stuff or images that
you did not upload.
What would you do after encountering
such a such a functionality?
Uh that's a really good question. I
would
probably report it right away and be
like there there's obviously some memory
corruption
um
going on here or kind of
unscraped memory being used.
I would
see I'd probably wait for the response
for that, would I?
Don't it depends how much else I've got
on, but I would definitely be interested
to to kind of
try and work out why.
I'm always
it's a really big driver for me is
always asking why is this doing this.
Um and often I'll I'll delve into
something that I really don't
won't necessarily help me directly there
and then.
Um but just trying to understand why
something happens.
And kind of take as many notes on that
as I can. And then off more often than
not I'll come like six months later I'll
come across something and be like, "Oh,
I understand this now because I spent
kind of two weeks
randomly looking at it six months ago.
What what's your experience with
reporting things like this where you see
something is clearly wrong, but you
cannot
prove that that you can leak some data.
What's what's been your experience with
this?
Very mixed. Very mixed.
But again, it's a good to me it's a good
um litmus test for a for a program, a
good good indicator on whether or not
it's going to be a good program to work
with.
If they take this and be like, "Oh,
yeah, that's definitely a
definitely a weird problem.
We'll we'll go look into it." Or if they
say, "Yeah, no, unless you can exploit
it, then we're not interested."
It's it kind of gives me yes, I want to
work with this program because they
sound really enthused about this this
sort of thing. Or yeah, fine, okay, it's
just another bug, move on.
Yeah, do you do you have some
tips about what to write in the report
when you report something not
immediately exploitable or do you think
it's just up to the program of of what
they do with it? Yeah, I mean I I always
try and include
always try and include the worst-case
scenario in in the impact without being
this is 100% what's going on
using
this could be an indicator of
um
but if you can understand like we were
talking about before, if you can
understand the kind of building blocks
and the what the next step would be,
you can put that in.
Um and I I have had cases of of exploits
or
identifying vulnerable software that I
didn't have a full exploit for
and saying, "Look,
uh in my guess, this would take two
weeks to develop a full
full exploit for."
Um
and
giving that bit of information and also
checking against the bounty table and
being like, "Well,
if their top bounty is 3K, 5K,
that's not worth
two full weeks of my time to to put into
this."
Um and I I have had that conversation
with a with a program being like, "I'm
pretty sure this is vulnerable." Um,
but
I can't justify spending the time to
write an exploit for it.
Um, that's again gone
both ways. Some being like, "Yeah, okay,
we you've given enough evidence to for
us to progress." And others being like,
"Nah, if there's no proof of concept,
then we'll just close the report." Yeah.
Yeah, and it is it is very often very
difficult for I think it's one of the
hardest things about bug bounty that
before submitting a report, it's really
really hard to judge what a program will
do, how the program will interact
because there's like zero rating of
programs, there is zero sort of public
reviews. So, usually before you report
something, you just know nothing about
the program. Yeah, and that's something
that's um
I learned very very well from uh Douglas
DyArkAngel.
Uh is he'll often report a kind of a
test report.
Um, to say, yeah, this is my first
report. I'll submit this one and see how
this one goes.
And if that's handled badly,
then
I'll move on.
And and look look at another program
before spending too much time there. And
I I think that's a really kind of clever
clever way of doing that.
Yeah, I like to after submitting the
first report, I like to just wait for it
to be resolved and then only then
continue
Yeah, 100%.
Although in the interview with NahamSec,
he he had a different approach. He was
like, "If I'm already on this program
and I'm already hacking, I might as well
just submit as many bugs as as I can
find quickly and and see later." But I I
just Yeah, yeah, I keep keep doing the
thing when I just report a bug and I
just wait and
Uh yeah, I
I think it really depends on what sort
of hacker you are. I think as we as we
kind of alluded to earlier, I
I report maybe
four bugs a month. I've been putting my
stats up.
I I have your stats here. Week 23, we
see 36 bugs. So, that's between one and
two per week. Yeah, so
so
let's say 1.5 weeks, so that's
that's not very many bugs.
Um,
whereas some people will have
I I see some people's kind of last
month's on on HackerOne tweets on on
Twitter and it's like, "I reported 99
bugs to to seven programs."
I don't think I've reported 99 bugs in
the past 2 years. It's uh
it's very different approaches. And if
you're the sort of person who's
reporting a lot of bugs, then yeah, I
can kind of get the idea of just find
what you can easily and uh and get those
in.
But for me, I'm I'm putting in huge
amounts of of hours on on single bugs.
Um, so if if one's handled badly, I'm
I'm going to spend those hours somewhere
else.
Yeah, and also you mentioned in other
interviews you spent a lot of time
writing the report. Are you still
writing really long reports or has the
time put into the reporting gone down?
No, that's I've I've fortunately brought
that down. Um,
and I've I've done that for several
reasons. One for my own sanity and uh
and time management because I initially
first few years doing bug bounty, I was
spending four five hours on a report.
Writing it, trying to make sure it's it
was perfect and and really easily
understood.
Um,
but I realized
the reports themselves were quite
difficult to read in the end because
they were so long.
Whereas an experienced bug bounty
um program just kind of want to know
what's the bug, how do I replicate it,
and
and what's the impact.
Um,
so I try to really land those few
points. And then I will add a little bit
more detail around it, be like, "Hey, if
you want to know anything else, just
just let me know."
Um,
and try and try and do it that way.
I What I have been doing is spending
much more time on proof of proof of
concepts and um
steps to reproduce.
And I've noticed that's much more
valuable than
spending longer on writing the report.
So, if I can give a a report with a with
a proof of concept that all the triage
team and all the program have to do is
kind of run it and it does everything.
I've Every time I've done that, the
report's always kind of sailed through
triage and so and the program have have
accepted it really quickly.
Um, and that was something I actually
did ended up doing with the server-side
browser stuff.
Um, was getting it so that
you could run commands on the back on
the back end and if it was uh for
example, a PDF renderer, the output of
the commands would actually end up in
the PDF that was rendered.
Rather than having to say, "Okay, so you
need you need to set up your own VPS and
listen for incoming connections on the
VPS and then
do XYZ."
It As soon as I kind of got it down to
all you need to do is run this on that
on the server and it you'll see the
output in a in a PDF.
One, it got me so many
bonuses on top of bounties. With
programs just saying, "Wow, that is
amazing."
And it made the the kind of whole triage
process much simpler.
Yeah. Yeah, I agree. I definitely also
lean into writing scripts to exploit
bugs, especially if it's complex ones.
I just laughed a little bit when you
said this because last um
last time I did that, I had the
a wireless account takeover. And you
needed to also use attacker credentials
for to exploit the bug. So, my variables
in the script said attacker attacker
username, attacker password.
And then the triager was like, "No,
Greg, it does not work." And I saw he he
sent me the screens the screenshot. And
clearly he put in attacker's password,
he put in victim's username. So, it was
attacker's username, victim's username.
I was like, "If you replace the attacker
password with attacker password, it's it
will work." I I think he
he deleted the comment in the triage my
bug he found. I do get it. I mean, the
triage team go through so many bugs
every day. I That's that's the other
reason I I try and
kind of get my reproduction steps down
really tight is
just they're looking at
kind of hundreds of bugs a week. And
they're not necessarily going to
remember from when when they read the
report and tried it the first time to
then when they tried it the second time.
Um,
so if you really hammer on those
reproduction steps and
uh proof of concept scripts, they just
make it make their life so much easier.
And if it it only really takes me an
extra 10-15 minutes to get to that
point.
But can often save kind of
hours of back and forth with um
with more information and all the rest
of it.
Yeah, so what are the things you stopped
putting in the report then?
Um, often an explanation of the bug
class and why it's
here in the in this specific instance.
Um, coming from a pen test background, a
lot of our reports were, "This is a
cross-site like there's a cross-site
scripting bug here. Here's five pages of
what cross-site scripting is." And so I
was writing all that out for for so many
reports so many times and be like,
"Okay, no, actually everyone knows what
cross-site scripting is. If they don't,
they can ask me later."
But if I can just get it down to
if I can get it down to kind of less
than a page to say, "This is the bug,
this is where it is, this is how you
repeat it.
Go."
Then everyone who's
very busy doing these programs and and
triaging and
investigating impact on the program side
don't have to wade through pages and
pages of report to try and try and get
to what they need.
Yeah, that's also why I don't use the
template that are on HackerOne or
Bugcrowd, they have templates.
And I'm 100% sure these triagers have
seen the templates so many times, they
can just say it out loud without even
looking at it. So, I I don't know I I
can't find a reason to put it in my
report as well. I just prefer to write a
description of where the bug is, what
are the steps to reproduce, and
and I assume even if I didn't know what
cross-site scripting is, probably this
template would not help much.
Yeah, and I I've come across
kind of complex bugs where
I have had questions asked me like,
"Actually, how is this? What is this
work?" And I'm I'm always happy to go
into more information if it's required
um from either the triage team or the
program team, but
if that's required, you you can never
guess if it's required up front.
So, I'll
try and make everyone's life easy and
and leave it out up front and if more
information is needed, be like, "Yeah,
great. Let's do this." And kind of get
into the into the details of it.
Yeah, so I have your stats open. 36
issues reported, 21 critical, nine high,
six medium. First of all, I I want to
reiterate what I said before, it is an
incredible ratio cuz also if recently
HackerOne started putting the the
percentage of reports in in different
risk brackets, and it looks like the
typical bell curve with the most amount
of mediums. Yet for you, it's
it's not this. But my first question is,
so what are the six medium mediums then?
Cuz I kind of already know what are the
the criticals. I I assume highs from
here cuz they're not that far. Maybe
there's some some
impact mitigation, but what are the
mediums?
Uh so, actually the mediums were all
remote code execution.
Just going through
Okay, so um so it's just a sandbox
environment or something like that. Just
checking, they seem to all have been in
uh yeah, remote code execution in Lambda
um serverless environments
where they
I think at least one of them was
um
indivi-
a lambda environment for the individual
users organization. So, it would only
have been a kind of intra
inter-organization compromise, which
given what the application was, wasn't
didn't pose much risk at all.
Um
and the rest of them just say they were
in lambda environments that didn't
process or couldn't access sensitive
data.
So, all of them were critical issues on
those were just downgraded to medium.
Do you try yourself the to to see what
permissions does the the lambda have or
do you ask the program to do it?
I've done it a few times. I normally ask
if I'm going to do it. Um
but it's not
I generally
think a program's going to understand
um the risk of
of something better than I am.
Like, I can I can spend time and try and
prove it,
but I could also spend time and move on
and report bug.
Um
if I believe a program's being
ingenuine, I
could push back a bit and I've done that
once or twice.
Um
there was one program I think downloaded
a
downgraded a bug from critical to medium
and I was like, "Yeah, but have you
considered
um that I like can access the the AWS
keys that
the lambda does actually stay
live and and could process other
customers data
and then they got back to me like,
"Okay, yeah, actually haven't hadn't
realized that." So, then they upgraded
that one back up.
But generally,
I will accept what a program um puts in
a report
and just move on and report something
else.
So, you usually when you find an RCE,
at at what point do you you just run a a
simple the simplest commands and you
reported it at
already?
Yeah, normally run kind of host name ID.
Um uptime is a good one.
Um one that tells you if it's a lambda
environment or not.
Uh
yeah, host name you name
uptime and uh
I think normally grab the working
directory as well cuz that often has the
application name in it.
And then I'll report it at that point.
Okay.
Also, some you had a blog post from a
few years ago about container escapes.
Do you still find bugs related to
containers? Not for a while, actually.
Um
a lot of the
container escape techniques that I was
previously using,
I've not seen in in a in a long time, so
I kind of stopped looking for them.
But yeah, I I did used to report quite a
few of those
um
in various environments. So,
I'm aware of one potential
dangerous container escape. I think it's
kind of a cross-container contamination
issue
that I
I want to look into more. I just haven't
found the time.
Um so, that's one I'll I'll go back to
at some point this year. The the program
I
I sent you a few weeks ago with with the
one particular functionality, it by
default it allows you to execute execute
code and
uh I think you should take a look at it.
Yeah, I
I certainly I want to want to spend some
more time on that one, actually. That's
uh
that was an interesting one. For a web
so for a web-based hacker, what do you
think is a good sort of area to also
develop these skill sets? Would it be
learning CI/CD related stuff? Would it
be maybe binary exploitation? Would it
be container escapes? What would you
think is a good supplement? Oh, that's a
really interesting question.
I've kind of done all of those because
of my lack of interest in web hacking.
So, coming coming from it the other way
around is is an interesting uh
I think as long as you're pushing
yourself and as long as you're learning,
that's what's got me into all of these
kind of areas of hack- of hacking. So, I
I kind of got into container
um exploitation when I was really
interested in containers and and
learning a lot about them and how they
worked.
Um and then find
and then I went out to find programs
that used containers that I could then
um exploit these issues on.
And that's always pretty much always
been the way I've
excuse me, I've gone about it is
finding a bug to exploit,
learning as much as I can about it, and
then finding other programs that I can
implement that knowledge on.
Um
and that's certainly been the case
coming back to your your spreadsheet.
Yeah, yeah, certainly.
Um yeah, that's a good one. And that's
that's pretty much how I hack.
So, I'll I'll play around with an app
for a while until I find interesting
functionality,
try and exploit that, and then see where
else on other programs I can exploit
similar functionality.
Yeah. So, if you were to find a new
program, if you are up to about to find
a new program,
what what things will you pay attention
to and how many programs you think you
will skip say thinking there's no
interesting functionality to you? 90% of
programs I'll skip over.
Um I'm I'm the worst in that case.
Um
I need something to be technically
interesting for me, and it it certainly
helps if I've got some affinity to a
program.
Um one I haven't spent any time well met
much time on yet that I really want to
is uh Epic Games.
Cuz I know some some
some good hackers who uh who've spent a
lot of time on Epic Games
and I've made some good good bounties
and some really interesting bugs.
Um
but on on my area of interest in
hacking, it feels like it's a really big
insurmountable program to try and get
try and get my head around.
But it's definitely on my list because I
know they use some really interesting
technology. They write a lot of their
own software.
Um so, it'd be a really interesting
technical challenge.
So, so how would it look like? Would you
just go to different websites from the
scope and try to find a a functionality
that you think is within your interest?
Yeah.
Kind of that kind of uh believe they've
got a few of their um
downloadable software in scope as well.
So,
that's where I'd probably start.
Um but again, that's that's purely my
area of interest. So,
Okay. What what bugs would you find in
the sort of local software? Um The the
there because I imagine for the for the
report to be critical or high, it must
be remotely exploitable.
So, what kind of bug would you would you
be looking for?
So, in other
software application?
I think that's
Yeah. American enough. Um Okay.
Something I used to focus on a lot would
be DNS rebinding to access local
um local servers.
So, there was one particular application
that would um it was kind of a a
development environment that had its own
um NPM
not quite connection. It was running its
own NPM server. So, node module server
that you that was running on a on a
local port.
And you could do I found out you could
DNS rebind to that and kind of get it to
install um
packages from third-party systems,
which I thought was really interesting.
So, it was
exploitable by having a developer with
that software open visiting a website
you control.
Okay. So, so you're talking about the
scenario where from the victim's browser
you connect to the local application.
precisely. Yeah. So, that's that's kind
of
the big risk area of um of software that
that runs locally on a system
is if you can exploit it from the
internet
by somebody visiting a website or
something like that.
You won't often find software that will
kind of
punch through a a firewall and and open
up a port to the internet and things
like that. That that just doesn't happen
these days, unfortunately.
Un- fortunately, I suppose for most
people, but they're less interesting.
Yeah, that's right.
How do you identify um
well, listing which ports is the
application listening to is easy, but
how do you then identify what to send to
this application so so it processes your
input? Um a lot of times I'll kind of
use Wireshark or or some other network
monitoring tool to see what happens
under normal use.
Uh so, under normal application use,
kind of
use the application to the the best of
my
understanding at that point and just
monitor the the the traffic to any any
local service that's that's popped up.
Um that's kind of the best way of
getting a handle on it. If you can't see
that, just start throwing kind of HTTP
um requests at local services
uh and see what they come back with.
Kind of throw random data at it, see
what it comes back with.
Okay. Let's let's come back to to the
Epic Games. Let's say you you found
something that is interesting to you.
How long how much time will you spend on
it before you decide Oh, of course, if
you find a bug, it's easy. The question
is how much time will you spend on it if
you cannot find anything?
Uh yeah, that's difficult one. If I'm
interested in the product and interested
in the company, I'm willing to spend
longer. Um
if it's
let's say some tax accounting software,
I will probably spend minutes on it
before I might know I can't do this. Um
I'm I'm very much an interest hacker and
I'm I'm fortunate enough to be. I if I
if I'm not interested in a program, I
will
skip over it quite quickly. And that's
something I really struggle with on a
lot of hack- life hacking events.
There are certain customers who I life
hacking event customers who I just don't
get on with their products and don't
find them interesting.
And knowing you've got to spend kind of
best part of 4 weeks going up against
something that I'm not interesting
interested in, I really struggle with.
My history with life hacking, which is
quite interesting, is
um
very variable.
I've
taken part in events where I've
submitted zero bugs whatsoever.
Um and I've taken part in events where
I've submitted
lots of critical bugs.
Uh, and then I don't think I've ever had
a mediocre event. I didn't see they're
all or nothing.
Yeah, he's very much fit still to the
image of your methodology that that we
sort of drew you in this interview.
Yeah. Do you find Do you find yourself
looking for
in these scenarios where you cannot find
something that really interests you, but
it's a life hacking event, so you still
dedicate time to it?
Do you find yourself looking for bugs
that you would normally not be
interested in?
Yeah, I mean
life hacking events are interesting
micro microenvironment where
often kind of low and medium bugs pay
reasonably well or very well.
So, I will report lower impact bugs
during the life hacking event. Um, if I
come across a bug, I will report it.
Whereas if I come across a low in
a normal bug bounty program, I'm I'm
almost certainly not reporting it.
Let Let's come back to the to the low in
normal bug bounty program. Do you still
note it? Do you Do you Are you very
meticulous about your notes?
No, for lows, no. It's something I need
No, something I need to get better at.
Um
and kind of learning to chain
lows to kind of higher impact
um, bugs is is definitely something I
I sh-
I need to get better at.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think uh
a lot of interviews with a lot of great
hackers, they they say something like I
have to get better in noting stuff.
Yeah, my my note taking is all over the
place. I
for a while I had a lot of excess uh
success
using um, kind of GitLab issues
and noting something as kind of
interesting functionality or a potential
bug or actually no, this isn't a bug.
And I was quite rigid for several years
doing that, and it worked quite well.
Um, but I got out of the habit of doing
that. Um, and then moved to
I think I use a Obsidian mostly these
days to
to note that, but I'm nowhere near as
rigid as I as I should be. So, I I
probably need to go back to kind of the
the
kind of GitLab GitHub issue style. I
think that That was my
That was my peak note taking, but I just
got out of the habit. Yeah.
Yeah, so I
obviously when when preparing for these
interviews, I listen to to all the
previous interviews I can find, and the
ones from like a few years ago, you you
would say more or less the same. And I
think in the critical thinking
interview, more or less 1 year ago, you
were quite positive about GitLab, about
your note taking, and and I think Yeah,
it's it's gone downhill. You you went to
a health retreat.
definitely.
Definitely. Okay, life hacking events.
I'm going to my first life hacking event
in in Las Vegas.
Fantastic. So, give me I'm I'm
incredibly happy. I I It was one of my
dreams to go there, so I'm I'm really
happy I go.
What are your tips for me before my
first life hacking event? God, can we
give away all my secrets now? Um
Start Just give me your common advice.
Start hacking as soon as you know who
the
who the targets are.
So, before you even know what the scope
is, start hacking on the programs.
And focus solely on the programs. So, my
my largest Can I interrupt you?
Maybe before because I don't even know
from the practical standpoint when is
the scope, when are the customers
revealed? Can you maybe like
Sure. So
Generally, um,
I only have experience with um,
HackerOne life hacking events actually.
They're the only platform I've
um, I've attended. Um, but generally the
the program will be released relatively
early.
If not with the invite, then kind of
when the
when all the invites have gone out,
pretty much at that point, you'll you'll
know what the
what the customer is or or quite early
on. Uh, then there'll be a scheduled
scope call, which is normally about 2
weeks before the event
which is right at the start of hacking
that they'll they'll be a kind of a Zoom
call
um, going through the scope of scope of
the event. So, there's normally probably
a
2-week window between knowing who the
customer is
uh, or who the program is to knowing
what the scope is.
Oh.
That's interesting. I didn't know about
this. That's a 2-week window that a lot
of people don't actually spend
focusing on the event. So, you might not
know the exact scope, but you can start
to understand a lot more about the the
customer and start looking at their
current programs and
uh, start preparing for for an event
like that.
And then this Then obviously when as
soon as you know the scope
you you'll know like how much of your
your pre-work is um, is useful for that
or for
uh, and can be can be used at that
point.
Um, so that that was my So, my biggest
success event uh, was with GitHub 2
years ago. Um
and that was as soon as I heard who the
customer was, I was 100% on their
program.
Uh, I think that was about 5 weeks of
focusing solely on the on their program,
which is the the longest I've ever done
on a single program. Um, and again, I
need to get better at that.
Uh Is Is this the one that Justin called
in the interview one of the best or the
best life hacking event performance and
Uh, yeah, possibly. I think I got all of
the awards except for the second place
and third place bounties because they
wouldn't give them to me.
Yeah.
But yeah, that that was a good That was
a very good performance um, and not one
I've been able to replicate since,
unfortunately. But um
Yeah, but in the window before when you
already knew the customer and you did
but you didn't know the scope, you would
report the bugs normally or would you
wait until the life virtual part of LHE
would start?
Uh, that was a really interesting one.
So, I did find two
I believe it was two uh, remote code
executions
during that
and kind of
window. And I was like, I don't feel
comfortable just holding onto these. Um,
so I I did report them right away. Uh,
and I believe they were considered
for the event because they were critical
then.
They appreciated that I let them know
rather than just sit on them for 2 weeks
or for
a week, whatever it was, but when I
found out versus when the the scope was
released.
Um
And that was
That
That wasn't a difficult choice. I was
like, okay.
The ethical thing to do with this is is
report it, and if they say
we won't include it in the life hacking
event, then I'm like, well, I've
reported a couple of critical bugs
anyway, so
that's still good good bounties.
Um, but I did ask for them to be
included in the the life hacking event
for that. Yeah, that's a good one. I had
no idea it worked this way, and I even
sort of organized my my travel or
more like lack of travel for for this
period to just be focusing hacking, and
I did not know about that the the
customer is known before the scope. So,
how how big part, let's say it let's say
GitHub. So, how big part of GitHub's
regular scope is in scope for the life
hacking event? Let's say typically, not
not this particular example. Again, that
really depends on the customer. Um,
some will have very narrow life hacking
scope.
So
that's happened several times that two
events that I've been
uh, been present with.
Others will have cuz they're such such
large um
pr- uh, programs, they'll have, okay,
this is an area of focus. This is an
area of focus.
Um, and we'll accept critical bugs from
anywhere.
It really
really depends on how they want to run
the
uh, run the event and what they they
want to get out of it.
So, it can be a very mixed bag.
Yeah. Yeah, I see. Yeah, thank you for
this. I I'll definitely definitely
include this in my
in my planning.
Um, how often do you collaborate during
let's say during normal hacking, and how
do you collaborate for life hacking
events? Uh, so
I've been doing more collaboration
recently with the server-side browser
stuff
where
a lot of people have kind of come up to
me and say, "Hey, I found this
server-side browser here. Do you want to
see if you can if we can work together
and exploit it?"
And that's worked out really well for me
cuz obviously I've learned
um, about a lot more instances of
exploitable
um
systems than I I would have found
myself. Um
But outside of that, I don't normally
collaborate
with with other hackers.
And that's mostly just due to my
my area of focus and my kind of hacking
schedule.
So, I work on a relatively strict strict
schedule. I I work kind of 3
3 3 and 1/2 days a week.
And I'm a
I look after my kids the uh,
the other time.
So, it's not as if I'm up at
I don't stay stay up late to hack very
often unless it's a life hacking event.
Um
So, I I don't want to impose on people
and be like, "Yeah, I'd love to hack on
this issue with you, but I can hack on
like Thursday morning only." Or or
something. I find that a bit
restrictive.
Um, I I have big fear of letting people
down, I think.
And that's uh, it's actually that's a
big thing for me in in life hacking
events. I've done a lot of
collaboration in life hacking events,
and I always feel really bad if I'm not
finding issues.
And I I get quite negative about that.
So
the last few events I've done solo
rather than as part of a team, and
that's taken the pressure off me a bit.
Okay, interesting. So, when someone
comes to you saying they have a a
functionality in a website that uses the
the
uh, Chrome browser you exploit it
together, I assume you you split this
bounty 50/50?
And then, let's say
1 year later, 2 years later, you find a
new Chromium exploit and you go to the
same program. Do you also split this
bounty with that person or not? Depends
on the
the specific instance. Sometimes I have,
sometimes I haven't.
Um
if it's a huge amount of work and a very
recent exploit, then I I tend to not.
Um
I've worked with some hackers where I've
told them that it's gone out of date.
Do they want to put the work in to
to exploit it? So, I have worked with a
few hackers who are interested in
um
doing Chrome exploitation themselves as
well.
Um and they've said no, yes or no. Uh
and
they've kind of gone off and done it
themselves or I've uh
if they obviously if they say no, then
I've I've gone off and done it myself.
I had an Yeah, I guess after your
interview, there more people interested
in this aspect.
Yeah, certainly. I had an interesting
one with um you seen
uh a few weeks back. I think actually I
think you put it on Twitter. Uh I'd
literally just got an exploit working
and I'd submitted it to a program. It
was I think it was maybe 3 or 4 days
after the the patch had come out. And
the next morning he messaged me being
like, "Oh, I've got this server-side
browser. Let's exploit it." And I'm
like, "Oh, is it this one I've just
literally reported?" And it turned out
it was. I was like, "Oh, that's really
embarrassing. I'm sorry." Yeah, yeah, I
saw they saw.
I just find it funny.
Um okay, you mentioned your your
schedule of working 3 or 3 and 1/2 days.
So, how does your typical week look
like? Yeah, so my both myself and my
wife work part-time.
Um and we both try and do kind of 3 and
1/2
working days a week over the over the
working week.
Um and we we look after our kids kind of
here at home.
Um
they're not in child care or anything.
So,
it's it's busy.
Um and when I'm with my kids, I try and
100% focus and be with my kids. It is
very easy just to kind of, you know, be
on Twitter or be on be on your emails
and and all the rest of it, but I I'm
try not to do that quite so much these
days.
Um
so I think I I generally have kind of
all of Friday
hacking and then half days the rest of
the week.
Um
but the good thing about doing kind of
bug bounties is it's very flexible. So,
uh I I said to you earlier, I took my
kids to the to the museum this morning.
Uh a day out just because we could. And
I'll probably end up doing some work
tomorrow just to fill in that time. But
um
so, it's not
specifically rigid. If I need to take or
if I want to take time away from it, I I
100% will.
Um
but I do try and put in the hours. Yeah,
so so Friday the full day full day is
like 9:00 to 5:00. Yeah, that Friday
will normally be kind of be 8:30 till
6:30 or something. Um so, slightly
longer day just to make up a couple
couple of hours that we missed during
the week.
Um
And the the half days? They'll be pretty
rigid cuz my wife works um a specific
schedule. Um they'll be pretty rigid
kind of 8:00 till 1:00 or
1:00 till 6:00.
So, you kind of interlace your working
hours and your wife's working hours to
be able to take care of the kids.
Yeah, that's interesting.
It is nice. I find it impressive cuz um
also in in
another interview, you just said you um
set up the the income goal that you
wanted to to achieve and you decided you
do not need to work full-time to achieve
it. And I do find it impressive. As much
as I find your hacking skills
impressive, I do find equally, you know,
the more impressive the the the ability
to just let go, be okay with the fact
that you could make more money if you
needed to, but just, you know,
preferring to spend the time with with
the significant people in your family.
Yeah, and that's uh
that can be a really difficult decision
for a lot of people. Um
I think we we didn't actually really
touch on it. Um but getting into bug
bounty, my wife and I lost a child.
Um and that that was actually
one of the reasons I I stopped full-time
work and kind of then fell into doing
bug bounty full-time.
Um but that experience really showed me
how
important family was to me.
Um
and I kind of at that point vowed I was
never going to go commute an hour each
way to an office and and sit there 5
days a week kind of 8:00 till
7:00 or whatever.
Um
I wanted to be with my family. Um
I'm so grateful I found bug bounty and
have been able to be successful with it
so that I can spend
that time with my family. And also, I do
earn a very good wage from it. So,
it's kind of the perfect role for me.
Yeah, you also seem very
um conscious about you do things that
you like, you do things that you're
interested in, you you do not work
full-time.
How did you get to this point? Cuz I
I I imagine it is one of the things,
being able to to do this, to let go of
other vulnerability classes, to let go
of the time you're not hacking. I
imagine it plays a key role in you being
able to be a full-time bug bounty hunter
for 5 years and and from from where we
are talking, you're not
going to end this this this thing
anytime soon.
Did you
Did Did it sort of happen naturally to
you that you landed at this point or was
it sort of consciously finding, learning
on mistakes? How How did it look like?
Yeah, that's
So, certainly learning from mistakes.
I've made a lot of mistakes in my both
both in my career and and and in bug
bounty. Um
but as long as I learn from them, I kind
of see them as a positive thing.
And I've learned a lot about how I work
certainly in the past 5 years.
I really struggle if I'm not interested
in something and that's
as I said, that's one of the reasons
I've I've kind of struggled struggled as
a web app tester is if I
if I'm not intellectually engaged with
with what I'm doing, I will
find it I will really struggle to be
motivated to do it.
Um
so,
I focus on areas that I'm interested in
and that gives me kind of that that buzz
to keep going.
As soon as I
I'm not interested in a in a subject
anymore, I will I will try and move on
and find another one that I am.
Um
but I'm also aware I could be earning
more money by just reporting cross-site
scripting everywhere I found it.
Um or or everywhere I I looked for it.
And that's
it's a conscious choice for me is at the
moment is to is that I can earn enough
money
I can earn my my target my target money
just focusing on the bugs that I want to
focus on.
So, my my fallback plan if if that ever
goes south is to report cross-site
scripting everywhere I find it. And and
hope to earn a living that way.
That's my
worst case scenario, I think. No, no,
that's uh
worst case scenario. It's a big joke I
have about not uh
not respecting cross-site scripting as a
vulnerability. It's um
I've I've come to respect it a lot more
recently, but uh
I used to think it was a bit of a
useless vulnerability, but How
proficient would be, for example, to
like exploit the integrity access
challenge with all the JavaScript
quirks? Are you even aware of these
things?
More so only through JavaScript
exploitation, actually. Um so, learning
a a battle of it
the quirks of has been a way of um
triggering exploits or vulnerabilities,
sorry.
Um but before I got interested in
uh JavaScript exploit Chrome
exploitation, I
I was a very bad uh JavaScript and uh
programmer and didn't really understand
a lot of the quirks.
But actually, there's there's a really
interesting
um
tool by uh Gareth Hayes is he came out
with recently, shazzer.co.uk.
Um which is around JavaScript quirks and
how they differ between browsers as
well. Um I've kind of just been keeping
up with that. See, he posts quite a few
updates to to that.
And that's
that's actually helped me find a couple
of cross-site scriptings that I've I've
needed recently.
Um
so, if you if you're not aware of that,
do check that one out. Yeah, and he also
also has a great book, JavaScript for
hackers. It's It has a lot of
the stuff you will need in in case your
worst case scenario. I'm really bad at
reading um technical books.
Um again, something I should get better
at. But uh I think I think I did buy a
copy um to support what he was doing.
But um
To To be fair, I have it as well, but I
have not read the the whole thing. I'm
I'm better at reading the
Yeah, it's blog posts that I normally
skim skim read, but I I feel if I do
that with technical uh technical books,
I'm not getting
kind of even 80% of the value of them.
So, Yeah.
Yeah, so for
how long did it take you to get to this
point where you know things that are
interesting to you, you know your good
schedule? How How much time did you have
to, let's say, waste? It's not a good
word, but you know what I mean. To to
find your things and how other full-time
bug bounty hunters or wanna-be full-time
bug bounty hunters can find out their
their perfect spot.
Sure. Yeah, so I think probably the
first year or so, if I look at
I mean, probably first 2 years of
full-time bug bounty, if I look at the
sorts of bugs I was reporting, they are
kind of a bit more all over the place,
the cross-site scripting,
um XXE,
uh zip path traversal, bugs like that
were the kind of
was what I was finding and reporting.
And then it kind of maybe 2 3 years ago
when I started to get interested in the
container stuff, that's where I
learned
that focusing on uh a specific
technology really worked for me.
Um and that's kind of how I've been how
I've been working since.
And I also find
I mean I'm I'm sure I'm sure you see it
as well. Sundays you just wake up and
you just cannot face doing
sitting in front of your laptop and and
and doing it. And I I've learned not to
push myself if that's the case. Um I
will just
if I can't focus, as soon as I realize
I'm not effectively focusing, I will go
and do something else for a little bit.
Yeah. For for me it's it's also
sometimes
kind of the opposite. Sometimes I feel
like not doing it, but actually
just over if you it won't go away if I
sit in front of the computer this
particular day, but if I see it's
sort of a theme of a week or something
like this, then I know just
um I need the discipline. Because
sometimes, especially if if I'm like in
traveling or different things, just the
I lack the discipline.
And even on a worst day, if I do just
spend the time working and and I just
build the discipline back,
it it it works well. So and it's super
hard to find which day is which.
Yeah, certainly. I'm I'm not disciplined
and that's um
it's something I've learned about
myself.
Kind of forcing myself into this um
work pattern that I'm doing now is
unnatural for me
um
with the with the child care.
And I found that really difficult. I
would much rather
work for
12, 14 hours when I'm really focused and
not work at all when I'm not.
Um that would be my ideal working
pattern,
but it doesn't work with my life.
Um
so I do force myself to work a little
bit more than I'm than I'm happy with.
But also if I'm really not getting
anything done, I will
write a blog post.
Um not that I'll ever finish that blog
post, but um it's an another thing about
it.
But uh or I'll I'll research something
new that I'm that I'm interested in
um rather than just kind of focus on the
money making side of it. I'll I'll try
and do something that
keeps me engaged.
Yeah. Do you have a lot of Anthony's
blog posts? Uh if I were to check,
there's probably about five or six that
I haven't deleted.
Um
some of them I get kind of two-thirds of
the way through and think, no, I I know
I'm bored by this, so I just delete it.
It's
I only want to be putting out kind of
blog material that I'm interested in.
So if I if I get bored while writing it,
I'm just like, no, that's that's not
going to get finished.
Um I've started my kind of um
server-side browser exploitation
compendium,
which I'm which I'm calling it of
everything I've learned from server-side
browser exploitation, and I will
hopefully get that out.
September time is my target, but that
might slip a little bit. Is it like a a
book-long thing?
Uh it keeps getting longer every time I
look at it.
Um
and I keep thinking of other
there's a lot of other areas that would
still need research, but I'm I don't
want to let that stop me putting it out.
Um cuz it's it's not only kind of
exploiting the the browser engine that
is that's not the only vulnerability, so
I do want to kind of put out all the all
the other ways that
server-side browsers can be exploited.
What's your motivation for for writing
blog posts, for publishing your stats on
Twitter? What's the goal of this? Um
blog posts is because I've learned so
much from other people.
Like nobody does this in isolation.
I've learned
from
thousands of hackers
um from blog posts, from Twitter posts,
from interactions.
Um it's my very small way of giving
back.
And the the stats is a really
interesting one. Um I can't even
remember why I started it.
I think I kind of put out the first few
and realized people were interested in
it.
And it kept me accountable as well.
And I think I do have quite a unique
style of only having, as you as you said
earlier, only having kind of 36 reports
this
so far this year, and that's nearly
halfway through the year.
A lot of people don't see that and don't
perhaps appreciate that survival way of
doing things.
And I've had a lot of questions around
that. They're like, like really only 36
reports? Are you
are you keeping that number low? It's
like, no,
if anything, I'm keeping that number
high.
Um
and I I like to put a little bit of
context with it as well
um
just to say, yeah, this was a bad week,
this was a good week. This is what I
focused on.
This is why it was low, this is why it
was high.
Um and I'd
I like to look back on on those
as well. It gives me something to look
look back on at the end of the year and
and reflect on.
Yeah. If if uh some of our viewers don't
know what we're talking about at the
moment, at AJX Chapman, the link
obviously will be in the description,
Alex posts every single week how many
issues has he reported until the
the current week and also with the
distribution of the risk of these bugs,
duplicates, informative, and a quick
note. So definitely definitely go to AJX
Chapman if you
uh if you want to see them. Alex, it's
been a great great interview. Just last
question uh did I have. What are your
plans for the following Are you going to
web learn web-related bugs
or are you planning to to keep hacking
like you are?
I would like to get better at web
hacking. Um so I've been taking part in
the the HackerOne um AWC this past
well, that I think it was about 2 weeks
ago.
Um
focusing on on the Amazon program for
that.
Really made me
want to spend longer on on those sorts
of of programs where it's such a big
company and such a big environment.
Um and speaking to uh Zizzionae,
um
who solely focuses on Amazon is really
kind of
inspirational uh to see how much he
knows about that single environment
um and the kind of knowledge he's built
up.
And I'd
uh I very much admire that and it's if I
can replicate kind of a small amount of
that in what I do, I would I think I
would be a lot better hacker. So let's
going to try and take some lessons from
from that and and see how I can
implement them in in what I do.
Um
and if that fails, I'll fall back on
what I know.
Which is not not a bad idea. Precisely.
It's working well for me so far.
Thank you so much for the interview. I
really appreciate it.
I don't know how about you, but I
certainly have learned a lot from this
interview. If you did too, please leave
a like under this video. And if you want
to see another interview with a
full-time bug bounty hunter, check out
the one with Justin Gardner. For now,
thank you for watching and goodbye.